Finding aid for Manuel Luis Quezon papers, 1909-1944
Bentley Historical Library
- Correspondents File
  - Jose A. Clarin (Senator, Bohol), 1917-1935 (Reel 47)
    (mostly Spanish)
    (much more than in General Correspondence--some re: changing name of Tulun to Sikatuna and his election and striving to be Senator protempore-1929 he died 1935)
  - Clark Bennett, 1933 (Reel 47)
  - Tomas Confesor, 1927-1943 (Reel 47)
  - Austin Craig, 1916-1927 (Reel 47)
    (mostly English)
  - Austin Craig (cont.), 1927-1937 (Reel 48)
    (much personal, interest; also much to do with his "Rizal's Own Story")
  - Dwight Davis, 1929-1931 (Reel 48)
  - Francis Dexter (Lawyer, Puerto Rico), 1917 (Reel 48)
  - Ramon Diokno, 1920-1940 (Reel 48)
    (mostly re: transcript of a litigation)
  - Harold Dollar (Dollar Steamship Liner), 1925-1934 (Reel 48)
  - Manuel Earnshaw (brother of Tomas), 1920-1933 (Reel 48)
  - Tomas Earnshaw, 1917-1932 (Reel 48)
  - Alfred Ehrman, 1920-1941 (Reel 48)
    (mostly re: S. F. business)
  - Joaquin Miguel Elizalde, 1935-1944 (Reel 48)
  - Joseph Evens (Col.), 1943-1944 (Reel 48)
    (one letter, August 26, 1943 re: resistance on Bohol, Senator Garcia)
  - George Fairchild (Senator), 1916-1941 (Reel 48)
  - Harriott E. Fansler (New York), 1912 (Reel 48)
  - James A. Farley letter, 1944 (Reel 48)
  - Ramon Fernandez, 1917-1934 (Reel 48)
    (mostly on business)
  - A. P. Fitzsimmons (M.D., Nebraska), 1931-1932 (Reel 48)
  - Abe Fortas letter, 1942 (Reel 48)
  - James Frear (Washington, D.C.), 1920-1939 (Reel 48)
  - Isauro Gabaldon, 1917-1923 (Reel 48)
    (heavy official correspondence in cables, etc. while in Washington)
  - Patrick Gallagher, 1916 (Reel 48)
  - Eugene A. Gilmore, 1929 (Reel 48)
    (official correspondence)
  - Fernando M. Guerrero (former secretary of the Philippine Senate), 1916-1927 (Reel 48)
  - Pedro Guevara, 1915-1932 (Reel 48)
    (mostly official correspondence)
  - Teopisto Guingona (Bureau of Non-Christian Tribes--later Judge 1st Instance), 1920-1932 (Reel 48)
  - Leon G. Guinto (later Provincial governor Laguna), 1918-1937 (Reel 48)
  - W. H. Lawrence (Banker) letter, 1919 (Reel 48)
  - Benito Legarda, 1911-1912 (Reel 48)
  - Benito Legarda (cont.), 1911-1912 (Reel 49)
  - James Harbord, 1910-1933 (Reel 49)
    (personal correspondence)
  - F. B. Harrison, 1917-1935 (Reel 49)
  - A. V. H. Hartendorp, 1929-1939 (Reel 49)
  - General Thomas Hartigan, 1920-1924 (Reel 49)
  - Harry B. Hawes, 1931-1938 (Reel 49)
  - J. Ralston Hayden, 1927-1943
    - JRH effort getting Quezon to come to Ann Arbor for a speech, November 1927--Bunuan advises Quezon to skip Ann Arbor visit, too small a crowd, mostly intellectuals [but he came November 28, 1927] (Reel 49)
    - Quezon to Hayden (as Acting Governor-General), letter re: Governor Cuenco of Cebu, Governor-Elect Cabahug and proposal for Cebu Jr. College, June 22, 1934 (Reel 49)
  - Roy Howard, 1930-1944 (Reel 49)
  - H. S. Howland (Colonel), 1915-1916 (Reel 49)
  - Senator Hughes, 1915 (Reel 49)
  - Cordell Hull., 1942-1943 (Reel 49)
  - W. A. Jones (Representative), 1912-1919 (Reel 49)
  - Winfield Jones, 1912 (Reel 49)
  - Leopoldo Kahn (Manila) (1920-1937) (Reel 49)
  - Maximo Kalaw, 1912-1916 (Reel 49)
  - Teodoro Kalaw, 1911-1931 (Reel 49)
  - Amzi B. Kelly (lawyer, Manila), 1916-1923 (Reel 49)
    (some re: Aguinaldo's activities, heavy continuing personal correspondence on issues of day--much advice to Quezon, legal and otherwise)
  - B. N. Kennedy (Publisher, Mansfield News), 1911 (Reel 49)
  - William Kenyon (Senator), 1915 (Reel 49)
  - C. King, 1929-1931 (Reel 49)
  - Grayson Kirk (Professor), letter, 1937 (Reel 49)
  - Jacob Lang (Educator), 1909-1915 (Reel 49)
    (English, some Spanish)
    (one item records number of American-Filipino mestizos in all provinces--table)
  - Jose P. Laurel cables, 1923-1930 (Reel 49)
  - Benito Legarda, 1912-1915 (Reel 50)
  - Marcial P. Lichauco (Professor), 1934 (Reel 50)
  - Mariano Lim, 1914-1923 (Reel 50)
  - Vicente Lim (formerly a Lt, Philippine Scouts), 1915-1933 (Reel 50)
  - John Livingstone (Chairman Democratic County Central Committee, Plaler, California), 1916 (Reel 50)
  - M. F. Loewenstein (Pacific Commercial Company), 1912 (Reel 50)
  - Justo Lukban telegram, 1915 (Reel 50)
  - Ramon Lontok (Reel 50)
  - William T. Lyon, 1913 (Reel 50)
  - Norbert Lyons (New York), 1912 (Reel 50)
  - General D. MacArthur, 1929-1944 (Reel 50)
    (mostly official, some clippings on MacArthur)
  - John R. McDill (Doctor, Milwaukee), 1912-1915 (Reel 50)
    (regarding his pro-Filipino activities)
  - P. C. McDonnell, 1915-1916 (Reel 50)
  - Frank McIntyre, 1912-1931 (Reel 50)
  - Paul V. McNutt, 1939-1940 (Reel 50)
  - Vicente Madrigal, 1917-1933
    - Quezon to V. Madrigal. Letter re: (in part) the coal mines in Cebu, October 8, 1917 (Reel 50)
    - V. Madrigal to Quezon. Reply to previous letter re: Compostela, Cebu mines, October 12, 1917 (Reel 50)
  - George Malcolm, 1917-1932 (Reel 50)
  - Federico Mangahas letter from New York, 1939 (Reel 50)
  - J. F. Marias letters (2), 1932 (Reel 50)
    (regarding imports-exports, San Francisco)
  - W. W. Marquardt, 1918-1922 (Reel 50)
  - Henderson S. Martin (Vice-Governor, Philippines), 1914-1916 (Reel 50)
  - Tomas Mascardo, 1913-1933 (Reel 50)
    (in Tagalog)
  - William E. Mason, 1911 (Reel 50)
  - Clarance B. Miller, 1912-1914 (Reel 50)
  - Tomas B. Morato, 1918-1939 (Reel 50)
    (re: Tayabas politics in part)
  - Frank Murphy, 1933-1944 (Reel 50)
  - C. H. Nance (Radio Corporation of America), 1929-1931 (Reel 50)
  - Manuel Nieto, 1920-1942 (Reel 50)
  - Gregorio Nieva ("Ypyung"), 1914-1940 (Reel 50)
  - Noriel (Case), 1915 (Reel 50)
    (English and "code"?)
    (include some correspondence with Osmeña)
  - William F. Norris, 1913 (Reel 50)
  - Martin Ocampo, 1911-1912 (Reel 50)
  - Antonio Opisso, 1913-1929 (Reel 50)
  - John E. Osburne, 1914 (Reel 50)
  - Camilo Osias letter, 1919 (Reel 50)
  - Camilo Osias ("Osi"), 1920-1939 (Reel 51)
  - Sergio Osmeña, 1911-1944
    - Osmeña from Pedro Guevara. 3 page letter re: in part Judge Concepcion, writes to Osmeña as "Presidente, Cebu, Cebu", also representative to Sr. Sotto, June 15, 1915 (Reel 51)
    - Osmeña to Quezon. Letter re: Osmeña's trip to Cebu, and situation there, January 31, 1925 (Reel 51)
    - Osmeña to Quezon. Letter re: Cebu politics, especially F. Sotto and Pedro Rodriquez, February 6, 1925 (Reel 51)
    - Osmeña to Quezon. Letter re: above, provincial convention, March 21, 1925 (Reel 51)
    - Osmeña to Quezon. Telegram re: party solidarity provincial, March 23, 1925 (Reel 51)
    - Osmeña to Quezon. 3 page letter re: political situation in Cebu plus clippings on it, March 24, 1925 (Reel 51)
    - Osmeña to Quezon. Long 7 page lette re: political situation in Visayas and Surigao and Misamis, April 1, 1925 (Reel 51)
    - Osmeña to Quezon. Radiogram re: a fire and call for aid [Cebu?], August 4, 1935 (Reel 51)
    - Osmeña to Major Ismael Ingeniero from Talusan re: Bohol, December 16, 1944 (Reel 51)
    - Campaign sheet, undated, probably for election, 1935 (Reel 51)
  - Rafael Palma, 1910-1931 (Reel 51)
    (mostly Spanish, some English)
  - T. H. Pardo de Tavera, 1911-1920 (Reel 51)
  - Quintin Paredes, 1922-1941
    - Salvador Betia to Q. Paredes. 3 page letter re: Visayas and HHC Bill, August 3, 1933 (Reel 51)
  - Elpidio Quirino, 1917-1938 (Reel 51)
  - James Rafferty (Ilocos Manganese Mining Company), 1919-1935 (Reel 51)
  - Benigno Ramos, 1916-1935 (Reel 51)
    (in English, Tagalog and Spanish)
  - Claro M. Recto, 1925-1939 (Reel 51)
  - Artemio Ricarte, 1917-1935 (Reel 51)
    (English, Spanish, much in Tagalog)
  - Lloyd Rice, 1937 (Reel 51)
  - Alejandro Ruces, 1926 (Reel 51)
    (re. misquoting Quezon in LaVancuaroia Taliba Tribune)
  - Eulogio Rodriguez letter, 1935 (Reel 51)
  - Maximo Rodriquez (Provincial Governor, Tayabas), 1920-1939 (Reel 51)
  - Jose E. Romero letter, 1936 (Reel 51)
  - Carlos P. Romulo, 1925-1944 (Reel 51)
  - Carlos P. Romulo (cont.), 1944 (Reel 52)
  - Theodore Roosevelt, Jr., 1932-1933 (Reel 52)
  - Jose Rosales, 1911-1939 (Reel 52)
  - Jacob Rosenthal, 1929-1935 (Reel 52)
  - James Ross, 1911-1933 (Reel 52)
  - Felix Roxas, 1911-1919 (Reel 52)
  - Manuel B. Roxas, 1923-1937
    - Quezon to M. Roxas re: Roxas' retirement, January 17, 1935 (Reel 52)
  - Pedro Roxas, 1910-1911 (Reel 52)
  - Alejandro Ruiz, 1912-1935 (Reel 52)
  - Primitivo San Agustin, 1912-1934 (Reel 52)
  - Teodoro Sandiko, 1920-1933 (Reel 52)
    (most re: Manuel Tabora vs. T. Sandiko)
  - Jacob Schurman, 1912-1933 (Reel 52)
  - John F. Shafroth (U.S. Senator), 1906 (Reel 52)
  - J. M. Shook (J. M. Shook Real Estate Investments), 1912-1923 (Reel 52)
  - A. S. Shuman, 1912-1913 (Reel 52)
  - Morgan W. Shuster, 1911-1933 (Reel 52)
  - Mr. Simms (Monrovia, California) letter, 1930 (Reel 52)
  - Vicente Singson Encarnacion, 1912-1934 (Reel 52)
    (in Spanish and some English)
  - Homer P. Snyder, 1919 (Reel 52)
  - Andres Soriano, 1929-1943 (Reel 52)
  - Antero Soriano (Representative), 1913-1933 (Reel 52)
  - Vicente Sotto, 1913-1935
    - V. Sotto to Quezon. Letter re:. V. Sottol's efforts to get repatriated, November 24, 1913 (Reel 52)
    - Quezon to V. Sotto. Response letter indicates he will help, December 7, 1913 (Reel 52)
    - V. Sotto to Quezon. Letter re: to election in fractions in June election, December 29, 1919 (Reel 52)
    - S. Concepcion to V. Sotto. Letters September 12, 1932, September 13, 1932 re: Esteban de la Rama, Clarin, etc. (Reel 52)
    - V. Sotto to Quezon; Letters re: Osmeña and his mission, 1933 (Reel 52)
  - Adolph Spitzel (American-Chinese Company, Hong Kong), 1916 (Reel 52)
  - Henry Stimson, 1927-1943 (Reel 52)
  - Harlan F. Stone (Chief Justice, U. S. Supreme Court) letter, 1943 (Reel 52)
  - Moorfield Storey, 1914-1922 (Reel 52)
  - William Sulzer (U.S. Representative), 1911-1913 (Reel 52)
  - Juan Sumulong, 1930-1935
    - J. Sumulong to Quezon and Paredes. Letter accepting invitation to join with mission to U.S., November 3, 1933 (Reel 52)
    - Quezon to J. Sumulong. long 5 page letter re: a review of Democrata activities throughout Philippines, July 22, 1934 (Reel 52)
    - J. Sumulong to Juan Nolasco. Letter re: Judge appointments, July 5, 1935 (Reel 52)
    - La Candidatura de D. Juan Sumulong" (3 page memo), undated; maybe August 13, 1923 (Reel 52)
    - Quezon to J. Sumulong. Letter 3 page draft, undated (Reel 52)
  - Richard K. Suther, 1943-1944 (Reel 52)
  - John Switzer, 1916-1934 (Reel 52)
  - William Howard Taft letter, 1911 (Reel 52)
  - Clyde Tavenner, 1910 (Reel 52)
  - Clyde Tavenner (cont.), 1911-1923 (Reel 53)
  - Carmi Thompson, 1926 (Reel 53)
  - Emiliano Tria Tirona, 1917-1931 (Reel 53)
  - James F. Tracy, 1913-1914 (Reel 53)
  - Grant Trent (U.S. Representative), 1914 (Reel 53)
  - J. P. Tumulty, 1914-1934 (Reel 53)
  - M. E. Tydings, 1934-1935 (Reel 53)
  - Basilio Valdes, 1937-1943 (Reel 53)
  - Louis J. Van Schaick, 1929-1933 (Reel 53)
  - Jorge B. Vargas, 1914-1940 (Reel 53)
  - Jaime C. de Veyra (Engalio), 1910-1927 (Reel 53)
  - Simeon Villa, 1913-1916 (Reel 53)
  - Vicente Villamin, 1919-1935 (Reel 53)
  - Ignacio Villamor, 1943 (Reel 53)
  - Juan Villamor (Provincial Governor Ilocos Sur), 1915-1935 (Reel 53)
  - Jonathan Wainwright, 1929 (Reel 53)
  - Chengting Wang (Shanghai), 1927-1934 (Reel 53)
  - Sumner Wells, 1943 (Reel 53)
  - O.C. Whitaker, 1916-1921 (Reel 53)
  - Charles B. Wilby, 1912-1915 (Reel 53)
  - H. Parker Willis, 1912-1919 (Reel 53)
  - Woodrow Wilson, 1912-1917 (Reel 53)
  - Erving Winslow, 1911-1918 (Reel 53)
  - Leonard Wood, 1923 (Reel 53)
  - Leonard Wood (mostly 1923), 1923-1927 (Reel 54)
  - Francis Woodruff, 1911-1913 (Reel 54)
  - Dean C. Worcester letter, 1913 (Reel 54)
  - Ben F. Wright (Auditor), 1925-1927 (Reel 54)
  - Luis Yangco, 1937 (Reel 54)
  - Teodoro Yangco (Most as Resident Commissioner Yangco), 1912-1921 (Reel 54)
  - Charles Emmett Yeater, 1917-1921 (Reel 54)
  - Jose Yulo, 1927-1936 (Reel 54)
  - Fernando Zobel de Ayala (Madrid), 1912-1934 (Reel 54)